panasonic.com 2018-07-26

# Privacy Policy | Panasonic North America - United States

## LAST UPDATED – 8/04/2016

We are pleased that you have elected to visit this Website (referred to herein as the "Website" or the "Site"), operated by, or on behalf of, Panasonic Corporation of North America on its own behalf (collectively, "Panasonic", "us" and "we").

Panasonic respects privacy rights, and is committed to safeguarding the Personal Information entrusted to us by our clients and visitors to our Website. Panasonic has implemented this Privacy Policy to govern the use of Personal Information that we collect through this Website, including Personal Information you send to us. This Privacy Policy does not govern Personal Information collected from any other source or in any other manner. This Privacy Policy is intended to provide you with information as to: (i) the type of information that is collected, (ii) how the collected information is used and with whom it is shared; (iii) how we intend to protect the information; and (iv) how you can access such information and have it modified and/or removed.

**UPDATED: 8/04/2016.**  This Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time. We will post changes to this Website, and we reserve the right to make changes without prior individual notice. Such changes are effective upon posting. Please review this Privacy Policy often so that you will remain abreast of Panasonic's current policies, including its policies concerning the gathering and use of information that may be collected on our Website. You are responsible for making sure you are aware of the provisions of Panasonic's most current Privacy Policy. You can tell when the Privacy Policy was last modified by checking the "updated" date.

## Overview -

  * Your California Privacy Rights
  * Collection and Use of Information
    * Personal Information
    * IP Address
    * Other Information
    * Your Consent
    * Use of Your Personal Information
      * Opting In and Opting Out of Electronic Communications
      * Do Not Track Signals
      * Use of Your Personal Information within Panasonic
      * Use of Your Personal Information by Our Service Providers
      * If Panasonic changes ownership
      * Lawful access, legal action and investigations.
    * Use of Cookies, Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics
  * Disclosure of Information to Non-Affiliated Third Parties
  * Retention of Personal Information
  * Your Privacy Choices – Limiting Information Sharing/Accessing Your Information
  * Protection and Security of Information
  * Links to Other Websites
  * Governing Law
  * Contact Us

**California Privacy Rights.**  Under California law, California residents who have provided personally identifiable information to a company may have the right to request a list of all third parties to whom that company had disclosed such information for the third parties' direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, along with a list of the categories of Personal Information that had been so disclosed. However, Panasonic's policy, as disclosed on this Website, does not currently permit Panasonic to share the Personal Information about you collected at this Website with non-affiliated third parties for such third parties' direct marketing purposes. Moreover, even if Panasonic's policy permitted the disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for such third parties' direct marketing purposes, because Panasonic provides you with an opportunity to opt out of such disclosure, Panasonic does not have to provide you with such lists. If you are a California resident who would like information on how to exercise your rights concerning third party disclosures, you may send an email to [CaliforniaPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com](mailto:CaliforniaPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com).

## Collection and Use of Information

**Personal Information**

Personal Information is information that uniquely identifies you, such as your name, address, email address and telephone number. At times, Panasonic may collect your Personal Information. For example, we collect your Personal Information if you create an account, purchase a product on the Website, or send us an email, and provide us with your name, address, telephone number and/or email address. If you are purchasing goods at our website, you may be asked to provide certain financial information, such as credit card information to our payment processers (which will be used solely for your purchase and not retained). We may also collect your Personal Information if you post, display and/or publish User Content on the Website. Additionally, when you enter any password-protected area of this Website, then this Website will recognize who you are and will collect information that you submit. Any information collected about you from this Website may be associated with other information that Panasonic has collected about you.

REMEMBER to exercise discretion and caution when you post content on this Website – any Personal Information so posted will not be held confidentially, and it may be publicly viewable. With respect to all communications you make to or through the Website, including but not limited to feedback, questions, comments, suggestions and the like: (i) you shall have no right to confidentiality in your communications and Panasonic shall have no obligation to protect your communications from disclosure; (ii) Panasonic shall be free to reproduce, use, publish, display, disclose and distribute your communications to others without limitation, in any way now known or hereafter devised; and (iii) Panasonic shall be free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how, information, data content or techniques contained in your communications for any purpose whatsoever, including but not limited to the development, production and marketing of products and services that incorporate such information, without any compensation to you.

_Financial Information._  Our payment processers process your payment for any purchases or sales made on the Website, to protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions, and otherwise as may be reasonably needed to manage our business in connection with your transaction. This financial data is not retained after your transaction has been completed.

**IP Address**

An IP (Internet Protocol) address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your internet service provider when you log on. Your IP address is not linked to your Personal Information but Panasonic does reserve the right to use IP addresses to identify individuals who threaten the Website or other users or visitors. IP addresses may also be used to help diagnose problems with the Website and to gather broad demographic information.

**Other Information**

When you access the Panasonic Website, Panasonic will automatically receive some information about your use of the service. The type of information that is automatically collected by Panasonic includes such things as the date and time of access of the Website, the Internet protocol (IP) address of the computer that you are using, the domain and host from which you access the Internet, your browser software and operating system, the referring website address, and the specific activities you are engaged in while visiting the Website. This aggregate tracking information is used to help Panasonic improve and enhance the website experience for all of its visitors.

**Your Consent**

We only collect, use and/or disclose your Personal Information with your consent. Your consent may be implied from the circumstances or may be expressly given for a particular purpose. For example, when you submit your Personal Information to us and post to our website, you are consenting to the collection, handling, use and disclosure of your Personal Information for the purposes identified or apparent at the time of collection and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

You must be 18 years of age to use the Website. Panasonic does not knowingly collect or maintain any Personal Information from children under the age of 13, and no part of this Website is designed with the purpose of attracting such children.

**Use of Your Personal Information**

We use your Personal Information for the purposes for which it is submitted, such as to reply to your emails, an interactive chat session, and inquiries, to allow you to participate in promotions, such as contests, and to purchase products through the Website. Your Personal Information may also be used in the following ways:

  * to deliver materials, information and services to you,
  * to give you notice of and/or resolve any problems that may arise in connection with our services,
  * to better understand the needs and interests of our customers,
  * to analyze the success of our products and services and Website,
  * to manage the Website's interactive functionality,
  * to help Panasonic improve and enhance the Website experience for all of its visitors, and customize the content on our Website,
  * for compliance with Panasonic's legal and regulatory obligations,
  * as otherwise reasonably required to provide customer services and maintain the Website,
  * to investigate potential breaches of the Terms and Conditions of the Website,
  * to investigate potentially unlawful activity,
  * for any other purpose outlined in this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms and Conditions of which this Privacy Policy is a part, and
  * as permitted by law.

We may also use your Personal Information to contact you via direct postal mail and/or electronically to the extent such activity is permitted by law, and, with your consent, regarding your relationship with Panasonic. This information may also be used to help Panasonic and its commercial partners deliver targeted advertisements, promotions and other initiatives to you.

_Opting in and opting out of electronic communications._  At certain points where Personal Information is collected on our site, there may be a box to indicate that you wish to receive certain information or communications from Panasonic. You may opt out of receiving electronic communications, such as emails from Panasonic at any time. In all of our electronic communications you will be given the opportunity to opt out of receiving future communications. You may also opt-out or change your preferences by logging in to your account on the website, navigating to the "My Profile" page and un-checking the checkbox labeled  **"Please add me to the Panasonic email list. We'll send you updates about sales and promotions"**  or by sending an email to [PanasonicPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com](mailto:PanasonicPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com).

_Do Not Track Signals._  Certain web browsers provide users with an option by which you may have your browser send a "Do Not Track" signal to websites that you are visiting, advising the recipient website that you do not want to have your online activity tracked. However, the way browsers communicate such "Do Not Track" signals is not yet uniform and accordingly, our Website does not take any action in response to such signals. In the event a final standard is developed and accepted, we may reassess how we should respond to such signals.

_Use of Your Personal Information Within Panasonic._  In order to provide you with efficient and reliable services and to improve product and service options available to you, Panasonic may share your Personal Information with our affiliated entities, in which case your personal information will be collected, used, disclosed, managed and stored in accordance with this policy as set forth herein. Our affiliates are companies controlled or owned by us, or companies that control us, or are under common control with us. This Website is intended for users in the United States and its territories and possessions, but if you use the Website from any country outside the United States, the various communications will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international boundaries, and by visiting the Website, you consent to these transfers as required or permitted by applicable law.

_Use of Your Personal Information by Our Service Providers._  From time to time, we may hire third parties to assist us with certain functions and services, such as data processing, computer software and website maintenance and development, transaction processing, promotional and marketing services, customer service, professional, legal or accounting services and/or business and sales analysis. Panasonic may share your Personal Information, without restriction (and regardless of whether you have chosen to limit our sharing of your Personal Information as collected on the Website), with such companies that we hire to perform services for us. In such situations, Panasonic requires that these companies agree to maintain the confidentiality of your Personal Information and to comply with the safeguards described in this Privacy Policy. These companies have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes. Furthermore, in compliance with privacy laws, we also provide our opt-out lists to non-affiliated third party companies so that communications sent by those companies on Panasonic's behalf do not get sent to addresses appearing on our opt-out lists.

_If Panasonic changes ownership._  We may also share your Personal Information as required to allow for a change in ownership of Panasonic and/or any of Panasonic's affiliated entities and/or of any business(es) to which the Website relates, and the related transfer of user information to the new owner. In the event of any such change of ownership, your Personal Information will continue to be protected by the terms of this Privacy Policy unless and until you are notified of a change.

_Lawful access, legal action and investigations._  Your Personal Information may be disclosed to non-affiliated third parties as either permitted by, or to comply with, applicable laws and regulations. Your Personal Information may be transmitted through and stored on servers outside your home country, and may be accessed by authorities in those jurisdictions. We may disclose Personal Information if we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected illegal activities or fraud, situations involving the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms and Conditions, or otherwise in accordance with applicable law. For example, Panasonic may disclose your Personal Information to comply with investigations by regulatory authorities or enforcement agencies in the United States of America or elsewhere, or to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud. Furthermore, Panasonic may disclose your Personal Information if it has a reasonable good faith basis to believe that it is required to do so by law, compelled by court order or legal process, or is reasonably necessary and/or appropriate to: (i) protect the rights, property and/or safety of Panasonic or any other person or entity; or (ii) prevent or take action concerning any alleged: (a) illegal activity or (b) breach of the Terms and Conditions or Privacy Policy of this Website.

**Use of Cookies, Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics**

The Website makes use of "cookies" - small data files which we may send to your computer on the basis of the information that we have collected about your visit. They contain information allowing us to recognize when you are visiting the Website and to keep track of your preferences. Through the use of a cookie, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on our site, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct on our site. Cookies are stored in your computer's browser or on your hard disk and can then be retrieved by the website. This Website uses two kinds of cookies: so-called "session" cookies, which are deleted from your computer when you leave the Website and are used purely to help you to navigate around the Website; and "persistent" cookies, which remain on your computer so that the Website can recognize you when you return. The Website also uses plug-ins. A plug-in is a piece of software which the user downloads into the user's web browser that allows certain web-based software to operate. In order to interact on the Website, you may be required to install certain plug-ins.

We may also use third-party advertising companies to target and show you advertisements when you visit the Website. These third-party advertisers may send "cookies" to your computer or other device to gather information about your preferences to provide you with advertising that is more likely to relate to your interests.

If you want to delete any cookies that were already sent to your computer or personal device, please refer to your web browser's "Help" facility. In addition, most web browsers can be set to prevent you from receiving new cookies, notify you before accepting cookies or disable cookies altogether. Details about this can normally be found in the "Help" facility provided with your browser. Please note that if you disable cookies you may not be able to take advantage of some of the Website's interactive functionality.

On occasion, Panasonic permits third-party advertisers and ad networks to place their own cookies on our Website to track visitors’ activities on the Site. This enables such companies to recognize visitors so that when those visitors visit a third-party website, advertising can be delivered that is tailored to their individual interests (whether for Panasonic products or for the products or services of others), based on what has been learned from the visitors’ activity on Panasonic’s Website. This practice is called “interest-based advertising,” and the practices of these third-parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

Panasonic offers you choices about the collection of information on our Site. Panasonic adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. If you decide you do not want to receive personalized ads from third-party advertisers and ad networks please visit [www.AboutAds.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices), where you can learn more about opting out from receiving interest-based advertising.”

This Website uses Adobe Analytics and Google Analytics, web analytics tools provided by Adobe Systems Inc. ("Adobe") and Google, Inc. ("Google") that help website owners understand how visitors engage with their website. We can view a variety of reports about how visitors interact with our Website so we can improve it. Adobe Analytics and Google Analytics collect information anonymously, and use cookies, and IP addresses, and they report website trends without identifying individual visitors. For more information related to Adobe Analytics, click here: <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html>. For more information related to Google Analytics, click here: <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html> You can opt-out of Adobe Analytics from this page: <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#4> and can opt-out of Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-On. For information about and to install Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, click here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

## Disclosure of Information to Non-Affiliated Third Parties

Panasonic will not sell, rent or market Personal Information collected on this Website to non-affiliated third parties for their marketing purposes, unless we have your consent. However, Panasonic may disclose aggregated statistics about visitors to its Website, along with anonymous information concerning individual visitors of its Website. We may combine anonymous information and/or aggregate information we collect with additional anonymous information collected from other sources. We may share anonymous information (including aggregate information) we collect regarding our users with third parties (such as advisors, promotional sponsors, and investors) for various business purposes including conducting general business analysis, and developing website content and services.

## Retention of Personal Information

Personal Information is retained to deliver our services, to otherwise fulfill identified or apparent purposes, and for record-keeping. At some point Panasonic may elect to destroy, erase or anonymize your Personal Information. Once anonymized, Panasonic undertakes not to re-identify the information.

Information posted on the Website may continue to be displayed on this Website, or on any successor website for as long as the Website or any successor site is available, and may be archived by third party websites. You may request access to your Personal Information in order for it to be updated or removed from a particular webpage by writing to [PanasonicPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com](mailto:PanasonicPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com). To the extent permitted by applicable law, we reserve the right to refuse requests for the removal of Personal Information from the Website.

## Your Privacy Choices - Limiting Information Sharing/Accessing Your Information

You may have the right to request access to the Personal Information that we hold about you, which includes the right to amend or correct that information, as appropriate, and to receive an account of how it has been used and a list of the organizations to whom it has been disclosed. In some circumstances, you may have the right to object to Panasonic's use of that Personal Information. If you are unable to access and update your information by logging into our website, you may request access and update your Personal Information.

To protect the confidentiality of your information and respect your wishes for how it is used Panasonic offers "opt out" alternatives. Specifically, you may instruct us not to share Personal Information about you with our affiliated entities. As noted above in  **"Opting In and Opting Out of Electronic Communications"**, you may also opt-out of receiving electronic communications from us at any time. You may make your privacy choice at any time and it will remain in effect until you change it.

If you would like to check, change, or confirm your privacy choices please contact us at: [PanasonicPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com](mailto:PanasonicPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com)

## Protection and Security of Information

Panasonic maintains reasonable standards of confidentiality and security for this Website and the Personal Information collected from this Website. Physical, technical, electronic and managerial procedures have been employed to safeguard the security and integrity of Personal Information collected through this Website. The Personal Information you provide is secured using industry standard security technology. Panasonic also restricts its own employees' access to Personal Information. However, it is possible that someone may intercept or access communications, transmissions and/or Personal Information. You must also seek to protect against unauthorized access to any passwords and/or accounts that you use in connection with this Website, and you should remember to log off of the Website once you have completed your activities on the Website or if you have decided to step away from your computer.

In the event that Panasonic determines that there has been a security breach that results in the unauthorized disclosure of Personal Information to a third party, Panasonic will promptly notify consumers whose Personal Information it reasonably believes has been compromised by posting information on the Website and, if email contact is possible, then also by sending an email notification with respect to the situation.

You acknowledge that the security of online transactions you conduct using the Website cannot be guaranteed. To the fullest extent permitted at law, Panasonic shall not accept responsibility for misuse or loss of, or unauthorized access to, your Personal Information.

_Your Responsibility for Your Username and Password._  If you have an account with this Website, you are solely responsible for the security of your username and password, and shall take precautions to keep your password private to prevent any unauthorized use. Neither Panasonic nor any other person or entity will be responsible for any losses, damages or consequences suffered due to careless or unauthorized use of a password. Please see the [Terms and Conditions](http://shop.panasonic.com/pna-terms.html) for this Website for further details.

## Links to Other Websites

From time to time, the Panasonic Website may contain links to other websites that are not controlled and/or maintained by Panasonic. Please be aware that these other websites may have different privacy policies which may subject you to different privacy practices. Please review the privacy policies of such other websites for information concerning what information is collected on such websites and how it is used. Panasonic is not responsible for the contents or privacy practices of any linked site or any link on a linked site.

## Governing Law

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the State of New York of the United States of America, without regard to its conflict of law provisions. Please click here to review the terms relating to [ ** _Disputes and Governing Law_**](https://na.panasonic.com/us/terms) for this Website.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or complaints concerning this Privacy Policy or our handling of your Personal Information (other than with respect to California Privacy Rights) you may contact us at [PanasonicPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com](mailto:PanasonicPrivacyAdministrator@us.panasonic.com).

Attn: Privacy Officer

If you have any questions concerning California Privacy Rights you may contact us at [californiaprivacy@Panasonic.com](mailto:californiaprivacy@Panasonic.com).
